

2nd Floor, River View Park Appt Manjri Bk, Pune 412307 panda.subhasish007@gmail.com 8433512306

SUBHASISH PANDA

Cloud and DevOps Engineers

I am a creative, passionate, and ambitious professional. I currently work as a senior engineer in DevOps and Cloud Infrastructure services. I have graduated from a Premier Institute and have 3+ years of industrial experience. I am a natural communicator and have excellent analytical and reasoning skills. I am capable of working both in a team or individually on any project with minimum help and supervision. My interests are Automation, DevSecOps, and clouds. In my free time, I either read a book or play some sport.

employment history

CapGemini Consultant Mumbai, Maharashtra July 2015 – Aug 2016

- Worked for both the CI/CM and DevOps team
- > Handling build and deployment of different projects using Jenkins
- > Working with various CI, CM tool such as Jenkins, Maven, Ant, ansible, etc
- > Created a CD pipeline using a custom made Jython script that automated the application deployment into IBM WebSphere
- > Wrote **Dockerfile** and created **Docker images** for different projects
- Capturing requirements from the client using a PM tool (JIRA)
- Experienced working in an Agile model of development

Crimson Interactive

Software Engineer

Mumbai, Maharashtra Sep 2016- Mar 2017

- > Worked on an NLP project
- > Developed different components of the NLP project using python's tornado server and NLTK library
- > Experienced setting-up, managing, and working with RabbitMQ
- > Experienced working in Agile Development Model
- > Introduced and implemented DevOps tools and technologies such as Jenkins, Docker, etc
- > Acted as a **scrum-master** for the group

Talentica Softwares

Senior DevOps Engineer

Pune, Maharashtra
Apr 2017-present

> Designed the IT Infrastructure for an IoT project using Openstalk Servers, Docker Swarm, custom Python Agent, and TICK stalk

- > Contributed a **Docker Swarm management tool** to the Open Source Community. Ref: <u>dockerWrapper</u>
- > Experienced in scripting languages such as **Bash**, **Python**, **Ruby**
- Experienced working on AWS cloud services (ECS, VPC, Lambda, Gateway, EC2 etc) and Google Cloud Platform
- Experienced in setting up a self-managed K8s cluster using KOPS
- > Experience in setting up cloud-managed K8s cluster such as Elastic Kubernetes Service (EKS) and Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE)
- > Experience in setting up
- > Experienced setting up CI/CD pipelines for k8s cluster using HELM, Jenkins, and Spinnaker.
- > Experienced in both creating an ECS cluster and setting-up CI/CD pipelines for that ECS cluster.
- > Experience in planning and supporting Production releases.
- Experience designing Cloud-Infra Optimisation models using AWS cloudwatch data
- > Worked with the **Incident Management Team**
- > Setup production graphs, checks, and alerts using Prometheus, Grafana, and Alert-Manager to catch and production outage
- > Configured Victorops, an Incident Management tool, to notify the team in case of any production incident
- > Provisioned AWS infrastructure for a project using terraform modules
- > Designed Configuration Management for a project using Ansible playbooks
- > Guide and Mentor junior resources in the absence of the supervisor.

awards and recognition

- ➤ National Finalist in TechGig Code Gladiator 2017 DevOps Hackathon
- > Spot Award from Organization for exceptional performance in Incident Management team
- > National level 1st prize in Techgig Online DevOps Hackathon 2017
- National Level 2nd prize in Techgig Online DevOps Hackathon 2018
- > Spot award from Organisation for identifying the inefficient service using Cloud Infra Optimisation model and hence saving \$147K for the client each month

objectives

I want to work as a Senior DevOps/Delivery Engineer in an organization, where I can work towards a goal/vision and where my daily work will impact the organization's product in a positive way

education

IGNOU Correspondence Course

Distance Learning

Master of Arts, Economics

Graduated, Jan 2018

Indian Institute of Technology(ISM)

Dhanbad, Jharkhand

B.Tech, Mining Engineering

Graduated May 2015

professional skills

programming	languages:
P O	

b. 08. a 8 .a 8 .a 8 .a.	
Python:	****
MySQL:	***

Operating System:

operating system.	
Linux, Windows:	****

DevOps:

CI tools (Jenkins, Bitbucket, Circle CI, Ansible, terraform etc):	****
CD tools (Jenkins, Code-deploy, Spinnaker, etc):	****
CM tools (Prometheus, Grafana, Nagios, consul etc):	****

Microservices:

Docker:	****
Kubernetes:	****

Managerial:

Microsoft Office (Excel, Word, ppt):	****
JIRA:	****

Clouds:

AWS: ★★	***
---------	-----

languages

English, Hindi, Oriya